Gustavo Adolfo Toledo Barandica

Neiva-Huila, Colombia

Phone: +57 3183718246

Email: toledo970501@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/gtolbar

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gustavotoledo97/



Professional Profile:

Full Stack Developer and Electronics Engineer, certified in AWS Technical Essential, CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials, CCNA: Introduction to Networks.

Knowledge and experience of more than 3 years, comprehensive management of technologies such as Spring Framework, Angular, SQL, Scrum methodology and AWS services; performing support, software architecture, web application design, based on programming processes, project management through the estimation and processing of requirements.

Strong problem-solving skills from results orientation, proactive, continuous support to work teams, investigative capacity, assertive, adaptability to change, focused on meeting goals associated with the IT sector, disciplined and constant.

Professional Experience:

JAVA / ANGULAR DEVELOPER - SOPHOS SOLUTIONS (January 2023 – Present)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- Development of unit tests and mocks for Comfama certificate app.
- Support of bugs for services in the app Cumplimiento for SURA in PL/SQL.
- Support for the bank's applications "Bancolombia" with AWS, Angular Framework, Spring Framework, and others.
- Service recharge of package is developed for Bancolombia, whose process is the buy of packages of mobile operators in Colombia.

Achievements:

- Coverage greater than 80% of app Confama
- 100% bug fix.
- Migration of AWS infrastructure accounts 100%.
- Bancolombia package service with Puntored from development to production.

Skills:

Java, Spring boot, Angular, Typescript, Azure DevOps, Microservices, Time management, PLSQ, AWS, DynamoDB, Docker, lambdas, PL/SQL, Junit, Mockito.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JVN TECNOLOGIAS (June 2022 – January 2023)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- Upgrade software JDK 1.7 -> 1.8, Oracle WebLogic 10.3.6 -> 14.1.1.0, Oracle coherence -> 14.1.1.0, JSF 1.2 -> JSF 2.x.
- Fixing of Bugs in ecommerce web application.

Achievements:

 Successfully achieved 100% upgrade of software modules and fixed compatibility issues with dependencies.

Skills:

JSF, Java, JIRA, Microservices, Time management, WildFly, jboos, PrimeFaces, PL-SQL, Services Web SOAP, Oracle WebLogic, Bitbucket

➤ FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - INGYTAL (May 2022 - August 2022)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

• I worked in the development of a web application for customs control in the Peruvian government, my area of action was in the backend structuring behavior according to the role, in the frontend I worked making screens according to the supplied mockups. The technologies used for the development of this were Spring Framework and Angular implemented under the architecture of microservices and microfrontends.

Achievements:

- Worked on the functionality of the behaviour of the application by roles 80%.
- Development and implementation of screens in the Frontend 100%.

Skills:

Angular, Spring Boot, SQL (PostgreSQL), Keycloak, Maven, Gradle, Micro Frontends (single-spa) y Microservices.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - TOLBAR Technology – (January 2022 – April 2022)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

 A - We developed a service to generate certificates using Jasper Report for a client with up-to-date advice. The technologies used for the development of these were Spring Framework and Angular implemented under the layered architecture.

Achievements:

 The company's certificate module is developed and implemented with Jasper Report 100%.

Aptitudes:

Angular, Spring Boot, SQL (MySQL), Jasper Report, Postman, Spring JPA, Spring Security, Services REST, Git

DEVELOPER - Stock Gestión Integral SAS – (February 2017 – February 2018)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- As a Software and Electronics Developer in the Drone area at StockGI, I played an integral role in the design and development of drone solutions. My responsibilities encompassed:
 - Java Software Development: I designed and programmed software in Java for drone control and monitoring. This included the creation of interfaces and functionalities to manage aspects such as battery, signal, altitude, and other critical parameters.
 - Electronic Hardware Development: I worked on the design of specific electronic components for drones, including printed circuit boards (PCB) and sensors. I ensured the efficiency and reliability of these components.

 Software and Hardware Integration: I achieved tight integration between software and hardware to ensure smooth operation of the drones.

Achievements:

Application and design for remote parachute launching Drone is developed 100%.

Skills:

Spring Boot, SQL (MySQL), C++, Design 3D, print 3D, Git.

Other work experience:

> ACADEMIC MONITOR - Universidad UNAD (June 2020 - December 2021)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

Algebra, Trigonometry and Analytic Geometry Monitor - 2021 General Physics Instructor - 2020

 Provide guidance material to the course and support students with doubts about exact sciences.

Achievements:

 Provide support material for the courses in the areas to be worked on, facilitating a didactic understanding of the course topics.

Skills:

Exact sciences, office automation, leadership, proactivity, knowledge transfer, time management, etc.

▶ BIOMEDICAL TECHNICAL ASSISTANT - EMCOSALUD (August 2014 – January 2016)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

• Corrective and preventive maintenance of biomedical equipment.

Academic Background:

[ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING], [4.0/5.0]

[Universidad Nacional Abierta y a Distancia - UNAD] [Neiva-Huila, Colombia]

Achievements:

- I became an Academic Monitor in the areas of General Physics and Algebra, Trigonometry and Analytical Geometry for 2 consecutive years.
- 75% scholarship for graduate studies.
- I completed postgraduate studies in Information Technology Management.

[INDUSTRIAL AUTOMATION TECHNOLOGIST], [February 2016]

[Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA] [Neiva-Huila, Colombia]

Achievements:

 Represent the department of Huila in the Robotics modality in the national WorkSkills of Colombia.

Complementary Training:

- [INTERMEDIATE LEVEL AT STRIDE] [March, 2023]
- [AWS cloud practioner] [December, 2023]
- [AWS Partner: Acreditación de economía de la nube AWS Entrenamiento de negocios] –
 [Diciembre, 2023]
- [AWS Partner: Sales accreditation (Business)] [Diciembre, 2023]
- [PRE INTERMEDIATE LEVEL AT STRIDE] [Julio, 2023]
- [Curso de Arquitecturas Limpias para Desarrollo de Software] [Septiembre, 2023]
- [Curso de Infraestructura Como Código en AWS] [Junio-2023]
- [Curso Profesional de DevOps] [Feb,2023]
- [Curso de Docker] [Ene-2023]
- [Curso Básico de Jenkins] [Dic-2022]
- [AWS Technical Essential (Spanish)] [Abril,2022]
- [CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials] [Mayo, 2022]
- [CCNA Introduction to networks] [Mayo, 2021]

Summary technologies:

- Spring Framework
- Angular
- JAVA
- AWS
- Azure DevOps
- JSF
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle) y PL/SQL
- JIRA
- WebLogic

- Jenkins
- Docker
- Gradle Maven
- GIT (Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket)
- C++ (Microcontrollers)

Other information of interest:

Availability to travel (passport).

Languages:

English: Intermediate level – B1

Spanish: Native